A Finding Aid to the Linda Farris Gallery Records, 1969-1995, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Artists and Exhibition files, 1969-1995, undated; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 6.6 Linear feet Box 2-9, OV 15
  - Exhibition files, 1975-1995, undated; 3.2; Archival Resource Key
    - "Introduction '75 Charles Luce Matt Glavin" (1975), Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Keith Beckley Jeffrey Bishop Norie Sato, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - "Linda Farris at Blackfish" (1982), Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - "Linda Farris Selects: California" (undated), Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - "My Neighbor the Kingdome" (1976), Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 27-29)
    - "My Neighbor the Kingdome" (1976), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - "Lawrence Miller / Lee Loveland" (1975), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - "Louise Hoeschen paintings and drawings / Leslie McKay Johnson American Collectibles Series: The Fiesta Miniature" (undated), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "Microsoft Art Exhibits" (1987) (1988) (1989), 1987-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Exhibitions", 1973-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
    - "New Ideas" (1978), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - "New Paintings" (1986), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - "New York / New Work" (1989), 1985-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
    - "1979" (1979), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
    - "Nola Ahola Coallges, Watercolors, Textiles / Maria Winkler Green Photo Transfer Drawings" (undated), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - "A Personal Veiw: Three Decades of Linda Farris Gallery" (1995), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - "Print Project" (1982), 1981-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "Print Show" (1977), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - "Self Portraits" (1983), Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 18-23)
    - "Sherry Markovitz / Judy Lerner Brice / Louise Hoeschen" (undated), Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - "3.2.1" (1980), Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - "Three Young Artists" (1979), Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "X-Change: 5 L.A. Artists - 5 Seattle Artists" (1983), 1981-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - "Yours, Mine and Ours: Glass Sculpture and Chandeliers by Ginny Ruffner, Paintings by Steve Kursh" (1995), Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Oversized, Archival Resource Key (Oversize 15)
- Events files, 1971-1990, undated; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Box 9, 14
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by event type.
  Events included anniversary celebrations, lectures and panel discussions, and receptions. Panel discussion series include "Conversations" as part of the Goodwill Arts Festival, "Focus I" and "Focus II." The "Farris Wheel" was a series of lectures, discussions and tours. Included in these records are 17 sound cassettes including recordings of "Art Now" lectures and "Focus" panel discussions, three are unlabeled and one is illegible. There is also Seattle's mayor's proclamation of January 7, 1985 as Linda Farris Day, found in the fifteenth anniversary file.
  - Farris Wheel - Notes and Brochures, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Fifteenth Anniversary file, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Lectures - Art Now, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Lectures - Office Wall, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Lectures and Panels, 1978, undated; Archival Resource Key; 7 Sound cassettes (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Lectures and panels presumably held at the gallery including Minimal Art/Post Painterly Abstraction, Panel Art of the 70s, Art Now Assemblage, Abstract Expressionism Lecture II.
  - Focus Panel Discussions, 1979, undated; Archival Resource Key; 7 Sound cassettes (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Focus panel discussions, possibly 2 copies of each, some spanning multiple tapes: The Galleries, The Critics, The Artists, The Collectors.
  - Unmarked Sound Cassettes, undated; Archival Resource Key; 3 Sound cassettes (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Unlabeled, appear to be related to other groups of sound cassettes above, possibly copies of lectures.
  - Miscellaneous Events, 1973-1982, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Ninth Anniversary, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Panel Discussions - Focus, 1973, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 15-16)
  - Panel Discussions - Focus II, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - Panel Discussions - Goodwill Games - Conversations, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Panel Discussion - Media Coverage of the Arts, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Panel Discussion - What's This New Art All About Anyway?, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Panel Discussion - What's This New Art All About Anyway?, Matted Wall Text, Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Reception - Northwest Artists, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Twentieth Anniversary Events, 1982-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Herb and Dorothy Vogel Visit, 1980-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Reference files, 1969-1994; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Box 9-10
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  Includes clippings, brochures, booklets, photographs and transparencies, correspondence, and notes. Subjects include collecting contemporary art, soviet artists, photographs of artworks, art controversies, New York art galleries and art world, the Otis Art Institute, modern tapestries, Pioneer Square, potential artists, and Pilchuck Glass School.
  - Art Controversy - New Mexico University Art Gallery, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Collecting Contemporary Art, 1976-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Financial Information, 1974-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Images, 1973, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Inside New York's Art World Tapes and Films Information, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Modern Master Tapestries, 1971-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - New York Art Galleries, 1978-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Otis Art Institute, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Artworks, 1980-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Photocopied Photographs of Artworks, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Pilchuck Glass School, 1981-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
  - Pioneer Square, 1973, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Potential Artists, 1970-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Seattle Art Galleries, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Tyler Graphics Ltd., 1975-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - U.S.S.R. Artists, 1989-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Financial, Sales and Legal files, 1970-1995; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 10
  Included in this series are sales records, price lists, receipts, and information on works out of the gallery, including loan and consignment agreements and correspondence.
  - Burns, Marsha - Consignments, 1983-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - California Board of Equalization - Sales Tax, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - City of Seattle- City Selects #3 Purchases, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Out of Gallery - Consignments and Loans, 1981-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Price Lists, 1977, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Receipts - Security Pacific National Bank, Saefco, and Seattle First National Bank, 1980-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Sales Records, 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Work Out of Gallery on Approval / Consignment, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Works Currently on Exhibiton Outside of Gallery, 1990-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Linda Farris Papers, 1972-1995; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 0.9 Linear feet Box 10-11
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by topic.
  This series contains articles by and about Linda Farris and the gallery, clippings, photographs, brochures and flyers, correspondence about arts issues and funding, notes and writings, and a certificate of appreciation for Festival '72 from Seattle Center. Topics covered include the owner's activities and curation outside her own gallery, articles written by Ms. Farris, the ArtFair/Seattle Advisory Committee, the Goodwill Games Visual Arts Subcommittee, the Seattle Art Dealers Association, Ms. Farris's participation in the campaign to keep the Henry Moore sculpture "Vertebrae" in Seattle, an Art for the YWCA project, University of Washington Henry Art Gallery board membership, her involvement in a lecture visit by collectors Herb and Dorothy Vogel, and transcripts of a 1975 Archives of Northwest Art oral history by Sally Swenson, and of a 1989 interview by Ted Rinaldo.
  - ArtFair/Seattle 1992, Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - ArtFair/Seattle 1993, Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Art/Fair Seattle 1994, Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Art/Fair Seattle 1995, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Art/Fair Seattle 1995, Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Articles by Linda Farris, 1981-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Articles by Linda Farris on Collecting Contemporary Art, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Articles by Linda Farris - Series of Three - Notes and Clippings, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 28-29)
  - Articles by Linda Farris - Series of Three - Notes and Clippings, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Certificate of Appreciation - Festival '72, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Clippings and Articles, 1978-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Political, 1975-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Goodwill Games - Arts Festival - Russian Artists, 1988-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Goodwill Games Arts Festival, 1989-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Goodwill Games - Visual Arts Subcommittee, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Henry Gallery University of Washington, 1984-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Interview by Ted Rinaldo - Transcript, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Moore, Henry - Vertebrae - Campaing to Keep in Seattle, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
  - Notes - Speeches and Articles, circa 1970s-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Oral History by Sally Swenson Transcript - Archives of Northwest Art, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Seattle Art Dealers Association, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - YWCA - Art for, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Printed Materials, 1970-1995; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Box 11-14
  Printed Materials include books, clippings, magazines, press releases, and exhibition announcements, brochures and catalogs, collected by the gallery. Subjects include Isamu Noguchi, Russian art, prints, northwest artists and exhibitions, and architecture.
  - Announcements, Brochures, 1973-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 18-19)
  - Book - Form and Meaning: Writing on the Renaissance and Modern Art, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Book - Other Sources: An American Essay, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Book - Works on Paper: American Art, 1945-1975, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Book - Seven Stones: A Portrait of Arthur Erickson, Architect, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Book - Isamu Noguchi, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Book - Between Spring and Summer: Soviet Conceptual Arat in the Era of Late Communism, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1974-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Clippings - Current Magazine, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1974-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1981-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 6-8)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1990-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Magazines, 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
  - Magazines, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Magazines, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
  - Magazines, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Magazines, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Exhibition Announcements and Exhibition Catalogs, and Printed Materials from Other Galleries, 1970-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, and Printed Materials from Other Galleries, 1970-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1-5)
  - Miscellaneous Exhibition Announcements and Exhibition Catalogs, and Printed Materials from Other Galleries, Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Press Releases, 1980-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 6)